# Xiao (Brandon) Han

Desk 01, 01BB01, University of Surrey, Guildford, Surrey, GU2 7XH, United Kingdom

🛮 (+44) 07529989025 | 🗷 xiao.han@surrey.ac.uk | 🋠 brandonhan.uk | 🖸 GitHub | 🛅 LinkedIn | 📂 GoogleScholar

### **Research Interests**

I am broadly interested in the field of Deep Learning. My current research interest lies in the intersection between Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing (*i.e.*, vision-language). My research goal is to build multi-modal AI systems that can be used in real-world applications (*e.g.*, e-commerce platform). My expertise includes but is not limited to vision-language pre-training and (parameter-efficient) adaptation, many vision-language tasks (*e.g.*, cross-modal retrieval, text-guided image retrieval, image captioning, text-based/guided image generation/editing), and some specific tasks (*e.g.*, person ReID).

### **Education**

University of Surrey Guildford, UK

Ph.D. Student Jan. 2021 - Present (Jan. 2024)

- Major in Vision and Signal Processing at Centre for Vision, Speech and Signal Processing (CVSSP)
- Supervisors: Prof. Tao Xiang (principal) and Prof. Yi-Zhe Song
- Fully funded by University of Surrey FEPS/iFlyTek Ph.D. Scholarship
- Thesis Title (tentative): Fine-Grained Multimodal Deep Learning

Zhejiang UniversityHangzhou, ChinaBACHELOR OF ENGINEERINGSep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

- Major in Information Engineering at College of Information Science and Electronic Engineering (ISEE)
- Cumulative GPA: 3.92 / 4.00 (88.13 / 100), Third-year GPA: 3.94 / 4.00 (89.46 / 100)
- Thesis Title: Deep Learning-Based Features Prediction for Mass Spectrometry of Protein

### **Non-Degree Academic Experiences:**

Visiting student with Dr. Li Zhang at ZVG, Fudan University	Shanghai, China
Research assistant with Dr. Changbin Yu at AiR, Westlake University	Hangzhou, China
Visiting student with Prof. L. Jay Guo at EECS, University of Michigan	Ann Arbor, MI, USA
Exchange student with iESR program at University of Notre Dame	South Bend, IN, USA
	Research assistant with Dr. Changbin Yu at AiR, Westlake University Visiting student with Prof. L. Jay Guo at EECS, University of Michigan

# **Work Experiences**

Noah's Ark Lab

London, UK

RESEARCH INTERN (PT)

Dec. 2022 - Present

• Mentor: Jiankang Deng

• Project: Image Generation/Editing via Diffusion Models

PixelShift.AIShanghai, ChinaComputer Vision Algorithm Intern (FT)May 2020 - Sep. 2020

Mentors: Zhiming Ma and Meng Zhang

• Project: Immersive AR application (Google MediaPipe) and deployment of generative models (TFLite)

———— Publications
Fublications

### Conference -

### FAME-Vil: Multi-Tasking Vision-Language Model for Heterogeneous Fashion Tasks

Xiao Han, Xiatian Zhu, Licheng Yu, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

FashionVil: Fashion-Focused Vision-and-Language Representation Learning

**Xiao Han**, Licheng Yu, Xiatian Zhu, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

**UIGR: Unified Interactive Garment Retrieval** 

Xiao Han, Sen He, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

**Text-Based Person Search with Limited Data** 

Xiao Han, Sen He, Li Zhang, Tao Xiang

CVPRW 2022

CV1 1(VV 2022

Under Review

Nov. 2022

ECCV 2022

Oct. 2022

Jun. 2022

BMVC 2021

Nov. 2021

# Preprint Large-Scale Product Retrieval with Weakly Supervised Representation Learning Xiao Han\*, Kam Woh Ng\*, Sauradip Nag, Zhiyu Qu Journal Inverse Design of Metasurface Optical Filters using Deep Neural Network with High Degrees of Freedom Xiao Han\*, Ziyang Fan\*, Zeyang Liu\*, Chao Li, and L. Jay Guo Jun. 2020

## **Open-sourced Projects**

### eBayChallenge: A modularized codebase for large-scale product retrieval (based on PyTorch Lightning and Hydra)

- https://github.com/01BB01/eBayChallenge
- Implementation of our solution for eBay eProduct Visual Search Challenge FGVC9 (CVPR2022)

### FashionViL: A codebase for fashion-related vision-and-language research (based on Meta AI MMF)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/mmf
- Implementation and extension of our paper FashionVil: Fashion-Focused Vision-and-Language Representation Learning

### CompFashion: A modularized codebase for text-guided image retrieval (based on vanilla PyTorch)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/CompFashion
- Implementation and extension of our paper UIGR: Unified Interactive Garment Retrieval

### TextReID: A modularized codebase for text-based person search (based on vanilla PyTorch)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/TextReID
- Implementation and extension of our paper Text-Based Person Search with Limited Data

	HUIIUIS & AWalus	
2022	2 <sup>nd</sup> Place, eBay eProduct Visual Search Challenge - FGVC9 (CVPR2022)	eBay, USA
2021-2024	Faculty of Engineering and Physical Sciences/iFlytek Scholarship	University of Surrey/iFlytek, UK
2019	Chunzhen International Exchange Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2017-2019	3 <sup>rd</sup> Prize, Academic & Outstanding Student Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2018	Yongping Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2018	3 <sup>rd</sup> Prize, National Talent Training Base Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2018	Honorable Mention Prize, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	COMAP, USA
2017	3 <sup>rd</sup> Prize, Physics Innovation Competition in Zhejiang Province (Theory Part)	Zhejiang Physical Society, China

Honore & Awards

### **Services**

### Teaching assistant at CSEE, University of Surrey

• EEM071 (2023 Spring) - Advanced Topics in Computer Vision and Deep Learning (Instructors: Prof. Song and Dr. Zhu)

### **Conference reviewer**

- IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023
- AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2022
- ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACM MM) 2022
- IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME) 2022

### Journal reviewer

• IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)

### Skills

**Programming Languages** Python, C/C++, MATLAB, ŁTEX, Verilog, JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML/CSS

**Frameworks and Tools** PyTorch, PyTorch Lightning, TensorFlow, Git, Docker, W&B

**Codebases** Meta Al MMF, HuggingFace Pipeline (e.q., Transformers/Diffusers), Google MediaPipe, timm

**Languages** 普通话 Mandarin (native), English (fluent), 한국어 Korean (beginner)

### References

Will be provided upon request